Rubinow, Isaac Max Papers 5616
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Isaac Max Rubinow Papers
1892-1945
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Rubinow, Isaac Max
5616
16.33 cubic feet
16.3 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
The personal papers of Dr. Rubinow who was active in the movement for social security from a medical point of view. He was also an economist and served in that capacity with th U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistices, the American Medical Association, and several Jewish welfare societies, including Bnai B'rith. The collection is composed of his correspondence, some of his articles and manuscripts.
8455925
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 15, 2005
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 06, 2019
Biographical / Historical
1875 Born in Grodno, Russia
1893 Immigrated to the United States
1895 Columbia University, A.B. Degree
1898 New York University Medical College, M.D.
1899 Practiced medicine
1900-03 Columbia University, Studied political science
1903 Gave up practice of medicine
1903-07 Examiner, U.S. Civil Service Commission
1907 Economic Expert, Bureau of Statistics, U.S. Department of Agriculture
1907-08 Member, Bureau of Labor Statistics, U.S. Department of Commerce & Labor
1908-11 Member, Bureau of Labor
1911-16 Chief Statistician, Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corporation
1913 First book published, Social Insurance
1914 Columbia University, PhD.
1914-l6 President, Casualty Acturial Society
1916-17 Executive Secretary, American Medical Association, Social Insurance Commission
1917 Expert, California Social Insurance Commission
1917 Director, New York City Department of Public Charities, Bureau of Labor Statistics
1917-18 Investigator, Federal Trade Commission
1919-23 In Charge of American Zionist Medical Unit (renamed Hadassah Medical Organization)
1923-28 Director, Jewish Welfare Society of Philadelphia
1926-36 Executive Secretary, B'nai B'rith
1929 Executive Director, United Palestine Appeal
1932- 33 President, National Conference of Jewish Social Service
1934 The Quest for Security published
1936 September, Died at the age of 61
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5001: American Association for Labor Legislation Records 5001 mf: American Association for Labor Legislation Records on Microfilm 5001 PAM: American Association for Labor Legislation Pamphlet File 5616 (A) mf: Isaac Max Rubinow Selected Files on Microfilm 5616 OH: Isaac Max Rubinow Oral History
Rubinow, I. M. (Isaac Max), 1875-1936
8455925
- At>, 1933-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  routine
- Abbott, 1928-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  correspondence with Edith Abbott, University of Chicago and Editor of Social Service Review re his literary and teaching activities; Grace Abbott, Director, U.S. Children's Bureau re dependency and delinquency statistics advocating the construction of a dependency index
- Adams, T.S., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  letter agreeing to support Rubinow's efforts to obtain academic employment from T.S. Adams, Washington University in St. Louis, Department of Economics
- Addams, Jane, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Correspondence re Jane Addams Memorial Fund
- Adler, Cyrus, 1902-1908 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  re the significance of Adler's appointment to Political and Social Ethics Department, Columbia University in 1902 and their mutual interest on "Jews in Russia" and Rubinow's article on the subject
- Aetna Life Insurance Company, David VanSchaack, Director, 1913-1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  letter to Rubinow (1913) criticizing AALL circular endorsing the Jackson-Murtaugh Bill by the New York Committee of AALL
- Affiliated Schools for Workers, 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  routine solicitations
- Agronsky, G., 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  correspondence with Agronsky, Palestine Zionist Executive re life in Palestine; Rubinow's criticism of the opening of Jerusalem University; possible criticism of Rubinow's decision to return to the United States, and Rubinow's appointment as Executive Director of the Zionist Organization of America
- Ak, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  family correspondence with immigrating relatives
- Al, 1930-1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  routine business correspondence; correspondence with Floyd P. Allen, Executive Secretary of Public Health Federation in Cincinnati re Mortality by Census Tracts in Cincinnati Ohio for 1930; Correspondence with W.H. Allen, Rutgers University Institute of Rural Economics re speaking engagements
- Allen, W.H., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  routine correspondence
- Allman, J.P., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  re Rubinow's decision to remain in lphia as Executive Director of Jewish Welfare discusses financial sacrifice
- Amalgamated Bank, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  routine family correspondence
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- American Airlines, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- American Association for Labor Legislation (AALL), 1912-1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Correspondence with John B. Andrews, Secretary, re compensation for blindness^ child labor; Rubinow's election as a member of AALL's General Administrative Council; resignation from the New York State Legislative Committee', compensation for federal employees', subjects for meetings; activities of Committee on Social Insurance and Program Committee; McGillicuddy Bill re P'mama Canal and Panama Railroad employees compensation', discusses various sections of Dern Bill (federal compensation act)', letter from Henry Seager, President of AALL to Rubinow re enforcement of labor laws, 6/2/15; routine literary
- AALL, 1916-1926 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  re speaking engagements; health insurance; labor unions in NY and NJ re social insurance legislation (12/1/1) letter from Rubinow to Andrews re his return to U.S. after four years with Hadassah Medical Organization; extensive notes and correspondence re reduction of the waiting period for workmen's compensation; Epstein, Andrews and Rubinow reviving the social insurance movement; workmen's compensation for maritime workers (8/25) and routine
- AALL, 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  re cooperation between Andrews and Epstein of the American Association for Social Security (AASS); reply to Florence Kelley after her criticism of work of AALL; unemployment insurance; financial problems of the AALL; medical care; meeting arrangements and routine literary
- AALL, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  letter re Rubinow's article which appeared in AALL Review and his criticism of it's handling by editors (10/33); rivalry between AALL and AASS; meeting arrangements; routine and literary
- AALL, 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  re unemployment insurance for domestic service; AALL Review's "Silver Anniversary" issue; and routine
- American Association for Old Age Security, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  letter to Jane Addams re old age pensions and financial support of AASS; minutes
- AASS, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  letter from Fraternal Order of Eagles, National Old Age Pension Commission re credit for old age legislation; Brookwood Conference; minutes
- AASS, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Includes minutes; correspondence re the criticism of Epstein's article; Elias M. Epstein re paper about Palestine
- American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1, Folder 24)
  brochure describing the Association, n.d.
- American Association of Hospital Social Workers, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- American Association of Social Workers, Cincinnati Chapter, 1932-1936 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Bulletins, form letters, routine correspondence
- American Association of Social Workers, National, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  correspondence re article; annuity plans; minutes
- American Association of Social Workers, National, 1931-1936 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Scattered issues of "The Compass;" and routine
- American Bar Association, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- American Civil Liberties Union, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  re Hamilton County (Ohio) Department of Public Welfare requesting Rubinow serve on a board of arbitration
- American Conference on Social Insurance, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Preliminary Program for 1st Conference (AALL)
- American Consul, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- American Economic Review, 1911-1916 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  routine literary correspondence
- American Economic Association, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  letter re presentation of paper by Rubinow at meeting of Association
- American Economist, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- American Education Press, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  request for critical review by Rubinow of publication
- American Education Alliance, 1911-1915 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- American Express Company, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  routine correspondence about family business matters
- American Federation of Labor, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- American Hebrew, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- American Home Economic Association, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- American Jewish Committee, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  re mss. for publication
- American Jewish Congress, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  letter to Rabbi J.X. Cohen of American Jewish Congress re uniting Jewish people
- American Journal of Sociology, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  re publishing mss. "Some Statistical Aspects of Marriage and Divorce"
- American Labor Yearbook, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  re establishing old age pension fund or old age home for men and women who have been in prison for radical activities, letter from Solon DeLeon, Director
- American Legislator's Association, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  re old age pension system for Pennsylvania
- American Liberty League, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  form and cover letter, "Survey of Economists' Opinions on Selected Current Issues"
- American Magazine, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  re mss. review
- American Medical Association, 1914-1917 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  re mss. for publication; attending and presenting paper at meeting of the Associate
- American Mercury, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  re literary correspondence
- American Museum of Safety, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- American News Company, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- American Petroleum Industries Commission, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  re federal gasoline tax
- American Public Health Association, 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  re paper to be read at annual meeting
- American Public Welfare Association, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  re article and speech on social security program
- American Retail Federation, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Mimeo of minutes and proceedings on conference re unemployment compensation legislation
- American Seaman, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  re urging Rubinow to help Henry Bullock become attorney for Social Security Board
- American Socialist Quarterly, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  routine literary
- American Sociological Society, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  re abstract of paper by Rubinow for inclusion in proceedings
- American Statistical Association, 1915-1934 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  correspondence with C.W. Doten, Secretary re publication of articles; appointment of Rubinow to Committee on Business Statistics of ASA
- American Student Zionist Federation, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- American Suffragette, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  re writing an article on household service
- American University, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  re development of Social Security Program
- American Workers Party, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  letter from A.J. Muste, Chairman, AWP re raising funds for publication "Labor Action"
- American Writing Paper Company, 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  routine business correspondence
- Anderson, C.V., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Andrews, B.R., 1927-1931 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Annals, 1903-1936 (Box 1, Folder 68-69)
- Appleton and Company, 1902-1913 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Ar, 1903-1931 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  family matters re history of Rubinow family; routine literary correspondence ("Arena")
- Armstrong, Barbara, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  correspondence re meetings on social insurance with Committee on Economic Security of which B. Armstrong was a member and Edwin Witte, Executive Director
- As, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  lengthy reply to questionnaire sent to Rubinow by Alfred J. Asgis, Allied Dental Council, NY, re economic aspects of dentistry and routine
- Associated Charities, 1932-1936 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Associated Charities of Detroit, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Association International, 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Assurances Sociales (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Astor, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Atlanta Federation of Jewish Charities, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Atlanta University, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Atlantic Monthly, 1905-1935 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Au-Az, 1930-1936 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  personal family matters; routine
- B & L, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Ba, 1919-1935 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  letter (1919) from two members of American Zionist Medical Unit giving appreciation for Rubinow1s efforts; routine literary correspondence; routine business correspondence; correspondence with American Civil Liberties Union (1935) Director, Roger Baldwin re debate between Herbert Bigelow and Frank Palmer
- Baker, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  personal correspondence; significant amount of correspondence between Newton Baker and Rubinow re anti-Semitism; copy of speech by Rubinow, "The Cloud on the Horizon"
- Baltimore, MD, 1918-1935 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  Correspondence re speaking engagements, Baltimore City Medical Society (1919) and Young Men's and Women's Hebrew Association (1928) and others in Baltimore area
- Bartlett and Company, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  routine personal and business correspondence
- Be - Victor Berger, House of Representatives, 1906-1936 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  re legislation and routine
- Bercowitz, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  routine literary correspondence re American Socialist Quarterly
- Berline, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  personal correspondence (Rosa and Alexander Berline)
- Bernheimer, 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Bernstein, L.B. - Executive Director, Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of Pittsburgh, 1930-1934 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Berridge, W.A. - Professor, Brown University, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  correspondent' re data on poor relief operations
- Beth Moses Hospital, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Better Housing Association, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Better Times, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- Bi, 1906-1935 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- Big Brothers Association of Cincinnati, 1930-1936 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Bigelow, H.S., 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  correspondence re possible conflict with Eagles in Ohio re the Ohio Unemployment Insurance Bill
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1917-1927 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  correspondence re speaking engagements; possible position available for Rubinow with Federation of Jewish Charities of Philadelphia (1923); personal and business correspondence
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  correspondence re old age homes, speaking engagements; financial assistance for Henrietta Szold; Zionist movement; Rubinow's acceptance as Executive Director of Zionist Organization of America, and personal
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  re Zionist movement; locating another position for Rubinow - Rubinow admits first big mistake -accepting position as Executive Director (5/2U/29); routine and personal
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  re unemployment legislation in Pennsylvania and routine
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  re anti-Semitic attack on Rubinow by Cincinnati Chamber of Commerce; unemployment insurance (Pennsylvania and Ohio); United Campaign
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  re unemployment legislation; attack on Silver, Leiserson and Rubinow for being "Russian born"; includes lengthy letters from Billikopf re situation of Jews in Europe; letter to Billikopf from Rubinow re raising funds to rescue Jews from Germany
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Billikopf, Jacob, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 107)
- Bl, 1914-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  correspondence with Louis Block, University of Wisconsin re compulsory insurance; routine literary correspondence and routine
- Bloom, Allan - General Secretary, Jewish Community Center Association of Indianapolis, 1926-1931 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  re activities of the Association; personal and family matters
- Bloom, Allan, 1932-1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  re recommendations for Bloom from Rubinow; personal and routine
- Bluestone, E.M., 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Dr. Bluestone of Hadassah Medical Organization in Palestine re problems with the organization
- B'nai B'rith, 1926-1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  significant amount of correspondence re activities of Organization with Benjamin Shoolman, President; William Phillips, Undersecretary, of State re Jewish problems in Germany; I.M. Golden
- B'nai B'rith, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  correspondence with Richard E. Gutstadt re financial difficulties of Organization; Arthur Adams re problems between San Francisco and Cincinnati offices
- Bo, 1912-1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Bogen, Boris D., 1929-1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  lengthy letter giving biography of B.D. Bogen by his son? who was President of Jewish National Conference and routine
- Bookman, CM., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  12 p. mimeograph address by Bookman, Executive Vice-President, Community Chest
- Boston, Massachusetts, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Boudin, L.B., 1912-1915 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bowery Savings Bank, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  personal financial business
- Bowman, Mrs. Frank K., 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  re speaking engagement, College Hill Community Forum before Clerical Association of Episcopal Church
- Br, 1910-1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  letter from David Bressler, Secretary, National Jewish Immigration Council (1913) appointing Rubinow as a member of committee to investigate and study extent of illiteracy and its causes among Jews; routine and family matters
- Brandeis, L.D., 1922-1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  correspondence re unemployment legislation; work in Palestine with Hadassah Medical Organization
- Brickner, Barnett R., 1931-1935 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  correspondence re J.F. Lincoln's statements about Jews; routine literary correspondence
- Brisbane, Arthur, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  re housing problems
- Brooklyn, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  correspondence re welcome party for Rubinow as new Director of Brooklyn Federation of Jewish Charities
- Brooklyn Bureau of Charities, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Brooklyn Federation of Jewish Charities, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Brookwood Labor College, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  letter from A. J. Muste re soliciting appeals
- Brown, 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  personal business correspondence; routine and personal
- Brutzkus, B, 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  re recommendations for Prof. Brutzkus for various positions
- Bu, 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Buffalo, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  routine business correspondence re speaking engagements
- Bureau of Corporations, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Bureau of Jewish Social Research, 1930-1934 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- By, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Telegram to Sen. William Byrne (NYS) from Rubinow re congratulations on passage of Unemployment Insurance Bill
- Ca, 1911-1936 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  re recommendation for positions; routine
- Cabot, Philip, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  correspondence with Cabot, Professor Harvard University, Graduate School of Business, re discussions on unemployment insurance
- California, 1911-1930 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Correspondence re drafting legislation for social insurance; letter from Paul Herriott, State Board of Control, Calif, re cost of health insurance system; Rubinow's work as committee member of California Social Insurance Commission
- Calling Cards (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Canadian Public Health Association, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  routine correspondence re speaking engagements
- Casualty Actuarial and Statistical Society of America, 1914-1933 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  substantial amount of routine correspondence re Rubinow1s position as Secretary of Social Insurance Committee
- Casualty Actuarial Society, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  routine correspondence -Rut'now founder and first President of Society
- Casualty Actuarial Society, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
- Cavers, D.F., 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  correspondence with Cavers, Editor, Law and Contemporary Problems, Duke University, re Rubinow1s "State Pools and Merit Rating" and "Merit Rating Under Unemployment Insurance," articles
- Ce, 1926-1932 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Ch, 1918-1935 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  re speaking engagements University of Chicago; routine literary correspondence with Chesapeake and Ohio Lines; Christopher Publishing House; Robert E. Chaddock (Columbia Univ.)
- Ch, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  Correspondence with University of Chicago staff re Rubinow teaching for summer (1928) and routine literary correspondence
- Chamberlain, Joseph P, 1914-1936 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Correspondence with Chamberlain, Professor, Columbia University, re German refugees; unemployment insurance; health insurance; Commons, Andrews Witte and Epstein mentioned
- Chautauquan, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  re literary correspondence Rubinow's article, "Compulsory Insurance of Working Men in Germany"
- Charity (Box 2, Folder 44)
  solicitations from various charitable organizations, n.d.
- Chicago, 1931-1935 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  routine correspondence re speaking engagements in Chicago area
- Chile, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  correspondence re Rubinow assisting with government of Chile on setting up insurance plan for public officials
- Chipkin, Israel S. - Chip'cin, Education Director, Jewish Education Association, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  re Jewish child population study and correspondence re group insurance for employees of the Association
- Chubb, Irene, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  correspondence with Chubb, Missouri League of Women Voters re Wisconsin, Ohio and New York Unemployment Insurance plans and Rubinow's work on Ohio Commission on Unemployment
- Cincinnati, 1926-1936 (Box 2, Folder 49-50)
  University of Cincinnati Seminar address as well as other engagements in Cincinnati; routine organization: and literary correspondence, personal correspondence and routine
- City Club of New York, 1930-1933 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  re membership correspondence
- Cl, 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Cleveland, 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  re arrangements with Rabbi Armand Cohen for addressing Cleveland Community Council and routine
- Co, 1911-1933 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  Correspondence with Winnifred Harper Cooley, National Secretary, Associated Clubs of Domestic Science re household economics and pure food; speaking engagements; correspondence with Alfred E. Cohn, re Hadassah Medical Organization's budget problems
- Cohen, Louis (also Joseph L. Cohen, Alfred M. Cohen, Henry Cohen, Saul Cohen, Albert Cohen and Morris Cohen), 1909-1936 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  re personal, literary and routine
- Cohn, Fannia (Box 2, Folder 56)
  Telegram requesting Rubinow to speak on social legislation and reply, n.d.
- Columbia University, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  correspondence with Professor Henry R. Segar, 1/5/28 re revival of social insurance and routine
- Columbus, Ohio, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  re various speaking engagements in Columbus
- Commerce Clearing House, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Committee on Maternal Health, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  membership correspondence
- Commons, John R., 1913-1917 (Box 2, Folder 61)